<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>U.K. Indicators For The Sustainable Development Goals</title>
    <description>Data Platform Prototype</description>
    <link>/sdg-indicators/</link>
    <atom:link href="/sdg-indicators/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 12:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 12:12:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>User personas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We want to provide a data site that is easy to use by everybody and has purpose. To achieve this, we want to understand more about who uses the site and what they need from the site.
This year we have started to research who uses the data site and for which reasons. So far, over 50 people from a variety of organisations have taken part. The research involved interviewing people face-to-face or by telephone. We spoke to people across government, from academia and the private sector.
We have also carried out some usability testing, too. We tasked people to use the site to find specific information. Then we asked them about their experience. This information has informed our decisions about how we develop the data site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our research has not ended. We will continue our user research and our usability testing for the lifetime of the data site. We always need volunteers so please let us know if you want to take part. Email us at &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-envelope&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&quot;&gt;SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-did-we-find&quot;&gt;What did we find?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We identified four main user types or personas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment-uk.github.io/public/blog/user_personas.png&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram showing summary of user personas on scale of data type needed from visual data to raw data in the following order: concerned citizen, connected influencer, fact gatherer, involved analyst.&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of contents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#concerned-citizen&quot;&gt;Concerned citizen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#connected-influencer&quot;&gt;Connected influencer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fact-gatherer&quot;&gt;Fact gatherer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#involved-analyst&quot;&gt;Involved analyst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;concerned-citizen&quot;&gt;Concerned citizen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;who-they-are&quot;&gt;Who they are&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone who has an personal interest in SDGs or related topics but may also have a professional interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;likely-to-say&quot;&gt;Likely to say&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tell me what the goals are and what is being done about them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-motivates-them&quot;&gt;What motivates them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have either a personal and/or political interest in the SDGS and want to know what they are about and whether they will make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-they-want&quot;&gt;What they want&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerned citizens want to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get a better understanding of the SDGs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;see how the UK is doing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;see how they can help&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;see if the SDGs impact them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;see what is being done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;behaviours-and-preferences&quot;&gt;Behaviours and preferences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerned citizens might arrive to the site from other public facing websites and are more likely to prefer SDG content from media outlets. They will often browse using handheld devices and may share links with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-must&quot;&gt;We must:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;explain the SDGs in simple terms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give simple-to-understand context of what the goals mean&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give them an overall view of UK performance against targets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;explain what is being to meet the targets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use visualisations to explain everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-must-not&quot;&gt;We must not:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;expect them to understand the data in the charts without any context&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use terminology and technical terms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;expect them to go into individual indivators to get a view of performance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;put lots of methodology and usage notes in their way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connected-influencer&quot;&gt;Connected influencer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;who-they-are-1&quot;&gt;Who they are&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone non-statistical working in the not-for-profit space or for a private sector organisation looking to make money around sustainable development activities. Might be an individual attempting to challenge or guide on government policy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;likely-to-say-1&quot;&gt;Likely to say&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Give me a tool that will support my ambitions and give me a louder voice.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-motivates-them-1&quot;&gt;What motivates them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connected influencers understand the SDGs but don’t necessarily allign to them. The SDGs provide a higher framework for them to align their work to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-they-want-1&quot;&gt;What they want&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connected influencers want to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use the SDG website to educate people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;help businesses develop sustainability strategies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;take content from the website and report on it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;influence policies and change them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drive change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;see how the UK and government and performing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;behaviours-and-preferences-1&quot;&gt;Behaviours and preferences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have a good knowledge of the SDGs and use the SDGs to champion the themes they work in. They use the website to begin conversations with others and use it in conjunction with the UN website amongst other&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-must-1&quot;&gt;We must:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provide alternate routes into data so that their users can understand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provide guidance on indicators that relate to the themes they work in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ensure commentary and analysis is easy to find&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;show relationships between different indicators&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;show UK progress early in the journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-must-not-1&quot;&gt;We must not:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;expect them to get their answers through data manipulation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;force them to approach each indicator separately&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fact-gatherer&quot;&gt;Fact gatherer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;who-they-are-2&quot;&gt;Who they are&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policy advisers in government departments who have been tasked with reporting on SDG progress and VNR, non-governmental organisations looking to understand what is going on in the UK and think tanks wanting to understand what the UK is doing and hold the government to account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;likely-to-say-2&quot;&gt;Likely to say&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I just need to quickly see what progress is being made and check the facts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-motivates-them-2&quot;&gt;What motivates them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They need somewhere that gives them a view of UK progress which doesn’t involve hunting through lots of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-they-want-2&quot;&gt;What they want&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fact gatherers want to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;see what progress is being made and understand any issues or challenges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;take content and report on it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;see performance against targets and understand the issues and choices being made&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;see progress towards collecting data and understand the issues and choices being made&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;access the data and check the quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;behaviours-and-preferences-2&quot;&gt;Behaviours and preferences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They come to the website quite often  and may copy data for use in reports, which report data around themes not goals and targets. They cite the website in reports and may mix data from other sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-must-2&quot;&gt;We must:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provide them with a view of UK performance at every level&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provide bite-sized summaries to brief them on progress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provide them with links to the physical source data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;show them targets early in the journey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provide them with a quick view of what data has been collected, jot collected and reasons why data was chosen or not collected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-must-not-2&quot;&gt;We must not:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;expect them to find the source data with a generic link&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;populate the website with out-of-date website&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hide facts and figures under complex levels of navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;involved-analyst&quot;&gt;Involved analyst&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;who-they-are-3&quot;&gt;Who they are&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Involved analysts can be a range of different people, who usually work with international data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A statistical audience working in or around the SDG framework.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users creating detailed reports as part of commissioned project work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Academia working in funded projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students researching set topics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custodian ageny analysts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;likely-to-say-3&quot;&gt;Likely to say&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I just want the data so I can do my own thing with it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-motivates-them-3&quot;&gt;What motivates them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They need somewhere to get some or all of the SDG data so they can answer questions for themselves or others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-they-want-3&quot;&gt;What they want&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Involved analysts want to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get data to take away and use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;see trends behind the data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;find outliers in the data such as ‘leave no one behind’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get all data or lots of data on given themes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mix data from other countries or sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;behaviours-and-preferences-3&quot;&gt;Behaviours and preferences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They will often collaborate with others to produce analysis to inform or challenge policy and will share their reports with a wider audience. They will often copy the data directly from the tables rather than download it and will often transform the data for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-must-3&quot;&gt;We must:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give them advanced routes in to the data from the outset&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;show them the targets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;show relationships between different indicators&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give them methodology behind the data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tell them if the data is comparable with other SDG data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-must-not-3&quot;&gt;We must not:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;put lots of commentary and top-level visualisations in their way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;make it hard to get lots of data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;expect them to navigate each indicator to geth the data they need&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;expect them to understand the difference between data on the UK NRP and the UN global database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this was an initial phase of user research with a small number of participants, we will carry out further research to validate the user types. Further research will be carried out with custodian agencies, concerned citizens, government SDG policy analysts, local authorities and master builders as well as other users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions about the user personas or our user research, or if you want to be involved with future user research, please contact us at &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-envelope&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&quot;&gt;SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, please complete our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.surveymonkey.co.uk/r/XFJZGVL&quot;&gt;short survey&lt;/a&gt; to give some feedback about the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/user-personas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/user-personas.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>User research</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>International work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Department for International Development has partnered with countries in Africa and Asia. We receive funding from the Department to support these countries with SDG reporting. We aim to improve the quality and availability of SDG data for these overseas partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have worked with three countries to help them create and use their own country’s data site. Ghana was the first country to copy the UK SDG data site. We &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ons.gov.uk/2019/01/18/supporting-ghanas-global-goals/&quot;&gt;held a workshop to help our colleagues&lt;/a&gt; from the Ghana Statistical Service set up their site. We also explained how to convert existing Ghana data into SDG indicator statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We repeated the process with our colleagues in National Statistics Institute Rwanda. We helped them create their own SDG data site, upload data and explained how to maintain the site. &lt;a href=&quot;https://open-sdg.readthedocs.io/en/latest/case-studies/rwanda/&quot;&gt;Their experience is given as a case study&lt;/a&gt; to help other countries set up their own data site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also worked with the United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD) to help the National Statistical Committee of the Kyrgyz Republic. Other countries can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://open-sdg.readthedocs.io/en/latest/case-studies/kyrgyzstan/&quot;&gt;learn from their experience in a case study&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any country or agency can create their own version of the SDG data site using &lt;a href=&quot;https://open-sdg.readthedocs.io/en/latest/quick-start/&quot;&gt;step-by-step online instructions&lt;/a&gt;. Over ten countries have copied the site without direct help, to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some countries choose to customise their site. For example, Kazakhstan has &lt;a href=&quot;https://kazstat.github.io/sdg-site-kazstat/&quot;&gt;added visuals to their homepage&lt;/a&gt;. Armenia has &lt;a href=&quot;https://armstat.github.io/sdg-site-armenia/3/&quot;&gt;added targets as well as indicators&lt;/a&gt; and reports national indicators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sustainable Development Goals promote the idea of collaboration. With that in mind, it is important to make sure the SDG community shares new developments. Open SDG shares software program code for additions, amendments and new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre for Open Data Enterprise (CODE) combined United States and United Kingdom program code to develop &lt;a href=&quot;https://open-sdg.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;Open SDG&lt;/a&gt;. It is a shared, open-source online GitHub resource. SDG community members can use the program code stored on the site to amend SDG data sites. The community encourages members to submit and review feature updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Countries can copy the entire of Open SDG to create a new data site from scratch. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-sdg/open-sdg/releases&quot;&gt;Open SDG releases&lt;/a&gt; incorporate any revised or new features. These include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;data visualisations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;accessibility improvements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;language translations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reporting status categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open SDG has provided updates to available features following requests from community members. Recent new program code allows people to &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment-rwanda.github.io/sdg-indicators/reporting-status/&quot;&gt;mark SDG indicators as ‘not applicable’&lt;/a&gt;, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked with CODE and the United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD) to develop a way to use data and metadata in SDMX format. We have fixed various data visualisation bugs particularly in relation to maps. We also and added language translations in German, Spanish, French, Russian, Kazakh, Armenian and Arabic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaborating with CODE has not only enabled us to speed up website development, but also helped promote Open SDG.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/international-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/international-work.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>International</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Funded work</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;sdg-work-across-the-office-for-national-statistics-ons&quot;&gt;SDG work across the Office for National Statistics (ONS)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) project funds specific work across the Office for National Statistics. In this update those teams that receive SDG project funding explain the work they have been doing directly related to SDGs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ons-centre-for-crime-and-justice&quot;&gt;ONS Centre for Crime and Justice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONS &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ons.gov.uk/2018/10/04/new-ons-centres-to-focus-on-the-public-policy-issues-that-matter/&quot;&gt;announced five centres focussing on key policy areas&lt;/a&gt; in 2018. Our [Centre for Crime and Justice] improves the understanding of the nature of crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, we reviewed all the ONS crime data used to report the SDG indicators. We have used the latest and the most appropriate data sources to update indicators as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key focus for us has been investigating SDG indicators for which data is not provided. This includes indicators on modern slavery, human trafficking and child exploitation (Goal 16). We have made progress exploring new research methods and identifying potential data sources to support these indicators. We engaged with stakeholders from across government, academia and the third sector to help shape the research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ons-centre-for-equalities-and-inclusion&quot;&gt;ONS Centre for Equalities and Inclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/aboutus/whatwedo/programmesandprojects/centreforequalitiesandinclusion&quot;&gt;Centre for Equalities and Inclusion&lt;/a&gt; was announced by ONS in 2018 too. We aim to work with others to ensure that the right data are available to address the main questions about fairness and equity in society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working with the SDG team to develop the protected characteristics which align with the SDG disaggregations. New data sources and methods could benefit work programmes. They could also increase efforts for disadvantaged or discriminated groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;centre-for-international-migration&quot;&gt;Centre for International Migration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migration is one of the main SDG disaggregations the United Nations requires countries to measure and report.
The Centre for International Migration has published a range of research outputs in the last year. The following research reports will provide input to SDG indicators. These reports give breakdowns by migratory status to provide evidence on the contribution that international migrants make to public services and the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/populationandmigration/internationalmigration/articles/internationalmigrationandtheeducationsectorwhatdoesthecurrentevidenceshow/2019-05-03&quot;&gt;International migration and the education sector&lt;/a&gt;: This outlines the impact and contribution of international migration on the education sector at a local area. This will provide disaggregations for indicators within Goal 4: Quality Education.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/populationandmigration/internationalmigration/articles/internationalmigrationandthehealthcareworkforce/2019-08-15&quot;&gt;International migration and the healthcare workforce&lt;/a&gt;: This draws on all available data on the migrant workforce in health care in the UK. This will provide a disaggregation for indicator 3.c.1; Health Worker density and distribution by migratory status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the coming year we will collaborate with colleagues across ONS to provide disaggregations for indicators related to birth rates and mortality using available data sources. We will also collaborate with colleagues from across the Government Statistical Service (GSS) to provide further disaggregations, specifically against Goal 4: Quality Education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;titchfield-city-group-on-ageing-and-age-disaggregated-data&quot;&gt;Titchfield City Group on Ageing and Age-disaggregated data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2018 the UN Statistics Committee endorsed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/methodology/citygroups/Titchfield.cshtml&quot;&gt;Titchfield City Group on Ageing and Age-disaggregated data&lt;/a&gt;. The main aim of our group is working with statistical organisations and others with a particular interest in ageing across the world to improve the measurement of ageing populations and older people. Age is one of the disaggregations required by the UN for measuring the SDGs. This is so that no one is left behind in progress towards the 2030 Agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed aligning our work to the SDGs at our &lt;a href=&quot;https://gss.civilservice.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Report-of-the-2nd-technical-meeting-of-the-Titchfield-City-Group-11-12-June-2019.pdf&quot;&gt;second technical meeting in the Republic of Korea&lt;/a&gt;. The four objectives for this work strand are to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;assess the data available to monitor the “Leave No-one Behind” pledge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;interface with the IAEG on SDG indicators and to identify data needs to monitor the SDG framework for older people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;contribute to harmonisation and standards for producing ageing related data for disaggregation of SDG indicators&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pilot innovative approaches to overcome challenges faced by NSOs in relation to availability and presentation of SDG data in relation to older people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past year we submitted a response to the Inter-Agency Expert Group (IAEG) for the SDGs 2020 indicator review. Over the coming year we will work on providing new age-related break downs of the SDG headline data for the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;natural-capital&quot;&gt;Natural Capital&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/nationalaccounts/uksectoraccounts/methodologies/naturalcapital&quot;&gt;Natural Capital&lt;/a&gt; links economic and environmental data. We use the resulting statistics to estimate the value of the goods and services provided by nature in the UK. We also provide environmental statistical support to the ONS SDG Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are developing statistics about where air temperature is cooled by trees and water. Our aim is to highlight inequalities between different geographical locations according to deprivation levels. This can inform sub-categories of headline environmental data reported about the SDGs in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are supporting the improvement of data reported for SDG indicators about marine protection. For SDG target 14.7 (indicator 14.7.1) we are working on linking data about fish stock sustainability and the fishing economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;environmental-accounts&quot;&gt;Environmental Accounts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK Environmental Accounts also link environmental and economic data. We have continued to help the ONS SDG team develop environmental related SDG indicators this year. We also highlighted the importance of SDG indicators within the UK Environmental Accounts in some publications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked with the ONS SDG team to write our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/bulletins/greenhousegasintensityprovisionalestimatesuk/2017#toc&quot;&gt;Greenhouse gas intensity, provisional estimates, UK: 2017 release&lt;/a&gt;. It highlighted SDG target 9.4 (indicator 9.4.1) about carbon dioxide emissions for which our data is used to &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment-uk.github.io/9-4-1/&quot;&gt;report the UK SDG statistics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We analysed the environmental impact of burning organic materials alongside its contribution to the UK’s renewable energy industry. Our article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/articles/aburningissuebiomassisthebiggestsourceofrenewableenergyconsumedintheuk/2019-08-30&quot;&gt;A burning issue: biomass is the biggest source of renewable energy consumed in the UK&lt;/a&gt; highlighted SDG target 7.2 (indicator 7.2.1). We are working to provide sub-categories for UK SDG data about air emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked with the Department for the Environment, Food and Rural Affairs (DEFRA) and the University of Leeds on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/methodologies/measuringmaterialfootprintintheuk2008to2016#toc&quot;&gt;Measuring material footprint in the UK: 2008 to 2016&lt;/a&gt;. The article presents updated estimates and discusses methodology for the UK’s material footprint. This work feeds into international decisions about the best methods for estimating material footprint. The data for the UK’s material footprint is used to report SDG targets 8.4 (indicator 8.4.1) and target 12.2 (indicator 12.2.1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geospatial work in Data Architecture 
We worked on a major cross-team project to produce data for how close people live to roads. The UK data is &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment-uk.github.io/9-1-1/&quot;&gt;used to report SDG target 9.1 (indicator 9.1.1)&lt;/a&gt;. Our project’s methodology can produce figures for every country in the world and was presented at the UN World Data Forum in Dubai. The project won the inaugural Government Science and Engineering Geography in Government Award. This work led to the World Bank reclassifying the indicator from Tier 3 to Tier 2. Tier 2 indicators have internationally established methodologies and standards available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also sourcing data and analysing geographic data to tackle Goal 15 (indicators 15.1.1, 15.1.2 and 15.4.1.) Spatial disaggregation of forest area as a percentage of total land area (indicator 15.1.1) for the whole of UK is now available. This data is available at country and local authority level. It is available for years 2015 to 2017 for Great Britain and 2018 for Northern Ireland. Data showing the proportion of important sites for terrestrial and freshwater biodiversity that are covered by protected areas (indicator 15.1.2) should follow shortly. We are also working on coverage by protected areas of important sites for biodiversity (indicator 15.4.1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried out exploratory work on marine protected areas for SDG target 14.5 (indicator 14.5.1). We have also worked on national exclusive economic zones managed using ecosystem-based approaches for SDG target 14.2 (indicator 14.2.1).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/funded-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/funded-work.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Data partners</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital Accessibility Testing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The commitment to “leave no one behind” is central to the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). It extends to making our digital content accessible and functional for all users regardless of any disability or physical impairment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment-uk.github.io/public/blog/accessible-definition.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image showing the dictionary definitions of the word accessible.&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have labelled the site according to the generally accepted phases of site development:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alpha:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beta:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data site where this update is hosted is still in a testing phase, so we are using the ‘alpha’ label. We want to move the site to the next phase known as ‘beta’. We needed the site to reach the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) ‘AA’ standard before we can label it as beta. This is a universally-recognised standard, designed to guarantee that assessed websites reach the predetermined accessibility criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We updated some of the site’s features before it was tested, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;making data tables and menus keyboard compatible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improving the high-contrast feature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;adding descriptive labels and alternative text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tested the improvements on a range of desktop and mobile devices using a variety of browsers and screen-readers.
The Digital Accessibility Centre tested the data site against the WCAG ‘AA’ standard in July 2019. The newly-accessible site was re-tested in July 2019 and passed, receiving ‘AA’ certification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With ‘AA’ standard achieved, the UK SDG data site is now considered accessible to all users. A new code release (0.8.0) included these accessibility updates on the shared code repository ‘Open SDG’. This means that any country is able to use these updates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/accessibility.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/accessibility.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>accessibility</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building bridges and changing lives</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We keep being told we need to bridge the gap between statistics and policy makers. So, Fiona and I went to a policy conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment-uk.github.io/public/blog/hlpf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of New York UN building lit up with SDG symbols&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/hlpf/2019&quot;&gt;High Level Political Forum on Sustainable Development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving in the Big Apple for the first time was not at all what I expected. No queues and no questions at security (my advice, let your boss go through first), no traffic on the way into the city. Everything was rather calm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t stay that way though: nine long days of seminars, side events, workshops, meetings and networking. Even an Ambassador’s reception (sadly, no hazelnut chocolate delights).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were asked to attend to support the Department for International Development (DfID). Our team had a large input to the UK’s first Voluntary National Review (VNR) which was presented at the event by the (then) Secretary of State for International Development, Rory Stewart. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Lq-yUE5-Mc&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;watch the UK’s presentation on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Voluntary National Review explores the work being done by UK government, individuals, charities, businesses and other organisations to achieve the 17 Goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We weren’t the only people trying to bring data into conversations – data was big news in every session, and not just for the few of us there representing statistical institutes. The UK VNR panel included &lt;a href=&quot;https://theodi.org/person/dr-claire-melamed/&quot;&gt;Claire Melamed&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of the Global Partnership for Sustainable Development Data. Claire &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.data4sdgs.org/news/ceo-claire-melameds-remarks-uk-voluntary-national-review&quot;&gt;talked about the importance of data&lt;/a&gt; and how it can shine a light on the progress being made, reveal who is being left behind and show where governments and others need to focus their energy and attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team works closely with a growing number of teams at ONS, including the International Development team (happy third birthday to them, by the way). Our work led to me being asked to speak at a breakfast session with our colleagues from DfID and the Ghana Statistical Service. What I had thought would be a presentation to bleary-eyed data enthusiasts was… well, just that. EXCEPT, imagine my surprise when our UK Parliament’s International Development Committee walked in. Pretty much all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told them about the latest developments in the world of Sustainable Development Goals in the UK:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;our work to source data for the UK SDG data site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ONS’ large-scale involvement with putting together the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/uks-voluntary-national-review-of-the-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;UK’s Voluntary National Review (VNR)&lt;/a&gt; (200 pages too long to read just now? Watch this 5-minute video instead).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how we are building APIs where possible to automate data collection, so that our website is sustainable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how we are using admin data from across ONS to monitor UK progress towards the Goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how we are using private business data for SDGs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how our crime team has used data from charities to supplement their reporting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also showed them disaggregations of SDG data, where you can see who is being left behind; who needs help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Omar Seidu, from Ghana, spoke about how our SDG team have helped Ghana build their own data site and how they have used this, and the VNR process, to improve the quality of their data. They report inclusive data on their website, showing the high levels of poverty in greater Accra, which has prompted policy makers to act to tackle this growing problem. It was powerful to hear how data can change lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spite of the early hour, and a panel of data people at a political event, it was a successful session. The audience were engaged and stayed on after to ask more questions. It was a strange thing having an MP waiting to ask you a question about microdata while you’re busy talking to the Shadow Secretary for International Development about regional data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think both policy and statistics took a few steps towards each other at this conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You haven’t heard of the Sustainable Development Goals? Richard Curtis’ Project Everyone has a colourful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalgoals.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; explaining the Global Goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jo Evans and Fiona Dawe&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/HLPF.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/HLPF.html</guid>
        
        
        <category></category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using APIs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our UK SDG data site requires data files to be in a specific format. Reformatting available data into this format is labour intensive. We are looking to automate the process of updating the data we report. This will enable us to focus on identifying sources and developing new methods instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working with Application Programming Interfaces (APIs). They allow two software applications to communicate. Websites across the internet use APIs to automate updates and changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to use APIs that will work with data published online somewhere else. For example, the ONS Gross Domestic Product (GDP) per head time series has a supporting API which makes the data available in a format we can use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have written software program code to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enable our data site to link with APIs used by other websites reporting data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the relevant new figures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Format the results so they are usable on our site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Print our indicator files ready to go on our site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been able to cut down the work we do to process updates to the data we report on our site. We are using APIs to update 15 different indicators, currently. By automating these updates, we can report the latest data faster too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are updating SDG data with APIs that communicate with ONS websites so far. We are investigating which other websites we can connect to using APIs in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about how we collect data using APIs please &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-envelope&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&quot;&gt;email us at SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/APIs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/APIs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Data exchange</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
