<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>U.K. Indicators For The Sustainable Development Goals</title>
    <description>Data Platform Prototype</description>
    <link>/sdg-indicators/</link>
    <atom:link href="/sdg-indicators/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 13:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>International work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Department for International Development (DfID) has partnered with countries in Africa and Asia and we receive funding from DfID  to support these countries with their SDG reporting. Our aim is to help improve the quality and availability of SDG data for these overseas partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open SDG software that we have used to build our SDG data site was developed by ONS in partnership with the Centre for Open Data Enterprise (CODE) and the United States Government. The software is open source and free to use, making it potentially accessible to all countries looking to create a data site to report their SDG data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have worked with three countries to help them create and use their own country’s data site. Ghana was the first country to copy the UK SDG data site. We &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ons.gov.uk/2019/01/18/supporting-ghanas-global-goals/&quot;&gt;held a workshop to help our colleagues&lt;/a&gt; from the Ghana Statistical Service set up their site and explained how to convert existing Ghana data into SDG indicator statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We repeated the process with our colleagues in National Statistics Institute Rwanda. We helped them create their own SDG data site, upload data and explained how to maintain the site. &lt;a href=&quot;https://open-sdg.readthedocs.io/en/latest/case-studies/rwanda/&quot;&gt;Their experience is given as a case study&lt;/a&gt; to help other countries set up their own data site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also worked with the United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD) to help the National Statistical Committee of the Kyrgyz Republic. Other countries can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://open-sdg.readthedocs.io/en/latest/case-studies/kyrgyzstan/&quot;&gt;learn from their experience in a case study&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any country can create their own version of the SDG data site using &lt;a href=&quot;https://open-sdg.readthedocs.io/en/latest/quick-start/&quot;&gt;step-by-step online instructions&lt;/a&gt;. Over ten countries have copied the site without direct help, to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some countries choose to customise their site. For example, Kazakhstan has &lt;a href=&quot;https://kazstat.github.io/sdg-site-kazstat/&quot;&gt;added visuals to their homepage&lt;/a&gt;. Armenia has &lt;a href=&quot;https://armstat.github.io/sdg-site-armenia/3/&quot;&gt;added targets as well as indicators&lt;/a&gt; and reports national indicators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sustainable Development Goals promote the idea of collaboration. With that in mind, it is important to make sure the SDG community shares new developments. Open SDG shares   software program code for additions, amendments and new features.It is a shared, open-source online GitHub resource. SDG community members can use the program code stored on the site to amend SDG data sites. The community encourages members to submit and review feature updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Countries can copy the  Open SDG to create a new data site from scratch. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-sdg/open-sdg/releases&quot;&gt;Open SDG releases&lt;/a&gt; incorporate any revised or new features. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;data visualisations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;accessibility improvements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;language translations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reporting status categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open SDG has provided updates to available features following requests from community members. Recent new program code allows people to &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment-rwanda.github.io/sdg-indicators/reporting-status/&quot;&gt;mark SDG indicators as ‘not applicable’&lt;/a&gt;, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working with CODE and the United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD) to develop a way to use data and metadata in SDMX format. We have fixed various data visualisation bugs particularly in relation to maps. We also and added language translations in German, Spanish, French, Russian, Kazakh, Armenian and Arabic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the international work we are doing, please &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-envelope&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&quot;&gt;email us at SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/international-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/international-work.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>International</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Funded work</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;sdg-work-across-the-office-for-national-statistics-ons&quot;&gt;SDG work across the Office for National Statistics (ONS)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) project funds specific work across the Office for National Statistics. In this update those teams that receive SDG project funding explain the work they have been doing directly related to SDGs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ons-centre-for-crime-and-justice&quot;&gt;ONS Centre for Crime and Justice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONS &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ons.gov.uk/2018/10/04/new-ons-centres-to-focus-on-the-public-policy-issues-that-matter/&quot;&gt;announced five centres focussing on key policy areas&lt;/a&gt; in 2018. Our [Centre for Crime and Justice] improves the understanding of the nature of crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, we reviewed all the ONS crime data used to report the SDG indicators. We have used the latest and the most appropriate data sources to update indicators as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key focus for us has been investigating SDG indicators for which data is not provided. This includes indicators on modern slavery, human trafficking and child exploitation (Goal 16). We have made progress exploring new research methods and identifying potential data sources to support these indicators. We engaged with stakeholders from across government, academia and the third sector to help shape the research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ons-centre-for-equalities-and-inclusion&quot;&gt;ONS Centre for Equalities and Inclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/aboutus/whatwedo/programmesandprojects/centreforequalitiesandinclusion&quot;&gt;Centre for Equalities and Inclusion&lt;/a&gt; was announced by ONS in 2018 too. We aim to work with others to ensure that the right data are available to address the main questions about fairness and equity in society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working with the SDG team to develop the protected characteristics which align with the SDG disaggregations. New data sources and methods could benefit work programmes. They could also increase efforts for disadvantaged or discriminated groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;centre-for-international-migration&quot;&gt;Centre for International Migration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migration is one of the main SDG disaggregations the United Nations requires countries to measure and report.
The Centre for International Migration has published a range of research outputs in the last year. The following research reports will provide input to SDG indicators. These reports give breakdowns by migratory status to provide evidence on the contribution that international migrants make to public services and the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/populationandmigration/internationalmigration/articles/internationalmigrationandtheeducationsectorwhatdoesthecurrentevidenceshow/2019-05-03&quot;&gt;International migration and the education sector&lt;/a&gt;: This outlines the impact and contribution of international migration on the education sector at a local area. This will provide disaggregations for indicators within Goal 4: Quality Education.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/populationandmigration/internationalmigration/articles/internationalmigrationandthehealthcareworkforce/2019-08-15&quot;&gt;International migration and the healthcare workforce&lt;/a&gt;: This draws on all available data on the migrant workforce in health care in the UK. This will provide a disaggregation for indicator 3.c.1; Health Worker density and distribution by migratory status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the coming year we will collaborate with colleagues across ONS to provide disaggregations for indicators related to birth rates and mortality using available data sources. We will also collaborate with colleagues from across the Government Statistical Service (GSS) to provide further disaggregations, specifically against Goal 4: Quality Education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;titchfield-city-group-on-ageing-and-age-disaggregated-data&quot;&gt;Titchfield City Group on Ageing and Age-disaggregated data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2018 the UN Statistics Committee endorsed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/methodology/citygroups/Titchfield.cshtml&quot;&gt;Titchfield City Group on Ageing and Age-disaggregated data&lt;/a&gt;. The main aim of our group is working with statistical organisations and others with a particular interest in ageing across the world to improve the measurement of ageing populations and older people. Age is one of the disaggregations required by the UN for measuring the SDGs. This is so that no one is left behind in progress towards the 2030 Agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed aligning our work to the SDGs at our &lt;a href=&quot;https://gss.civilservice.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Report-of-the-2nd-technical-meeting-of-the-Titchfield-City-Group-11-12-June-2019.pdf&quot;&gt;second technical meeting in the Republic of Korea&lt;/a&gt;. The four objectives for this work strand are to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;assess the data available to monitor the “Leave No-one Behind” pledge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;interface with the IAEG on SDG indicators and to identify data needs to monitor the SDG framework for older people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;contribute to harmonisation and standards for producing ageing related data for disaggregation of SDG indicators&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pilot innovative approaches to overcome challenges faced by NSOs in relation to availability and presentation of SDG data in relation to older people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past year we submitted a response to the Inter-Agency Expert Group (IAEG) for the SDGs 2020 indicator review. Over the coming year we will work on providing new age-related break downs of the SDG headline data for the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;natural-capital&quot;&gt;Natural Capital&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/nationalaccounts/uksectoraccounts/methodologies/naturalcapital&quot;&gt;Natural Capital&lt;/a&gt; links economic and environmental data. We use the resulting statistics to estimate the value of the goods and services provided by nature in the UK. We also provide environmental statistical support to the ONS SDG Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are developing statistics about where air temperature is cooled by trees and water. Our aim is to highlight inequalities between different geographical locations according to deprivation levels. This can inform sub-categories of headline environmental data reported about the SDGs in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are supporting the improvement of data reported for SDG indicators about marine protection. For SDG target 14.7 (indicator 14.7.1) we are working on linking data about fish stock sustainability and the fishing economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;environmental-accounts&quot;&gt;Environmental Accounts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK Environmental Accounts also link environmental and economic data. We have continued to help the ONS SDG team develop environmental related SDG indicators this year. We also highlighted the importance of SDG indicators within the UK Environmental Accounts in some publications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked with the ONS SDG team to write our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/bulletins/greenhousegasintensityprovisionalestimatesuk/2017#toc&quot;&gt;Greenhouse gas intensity, provisional estimates, UK: 2017 release&lt;/a&gt;. It highlighted SDG target 9.4 (indicator 9.4.1) about carbon dioxide emissions for which our data is used to &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment-uk.github.io/9-4-1/&quot;&gt;report the UK SDG statistics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We analysed the environmental impact of burning organic materials alongside its contribution to the UK’s renewable energy industry. Our article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/articles/aburningissuebiomassisthebiggestsourceofrenewableenergyconsumedintheuk/2019-08-30&quot;&gt;A burning issue: biomass is the biggest source of renewable energy consumed in the UK&lt;/a&gt; highlighted SDG target 7.2 (indicator 7.2.1). We are working to provide sub-categories for UK SDG data about air emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked with the Department for the Environment, Food and Rural Affairs (DEFRA) and the University of Leeds on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/methodologies/measuringmaterialfootprintintheuk2008to2016#toc&quot;&gt;Measuring material footprint in the UK: 2008 to 2016&lt;/a&gt;. The article presents updated estimates and discusses methodology for the UK’s material footprint. This work feeds into international decisions about the best methods for estimating material footprint. The data for the UK’s material footprint is used to report SDG targets 8.4 (indicator 8.4.1) and target 12.2 (indicator 12.2.1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;geospatial-work-in-data-architecture&quot;&gt;Geospatial work in Data Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We worked on a major cross-team project to produce data for how close people live to roads. The UK data is &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment-uk.github.io/9-1-1/&quot;&gt;used to report SDG target 9.1 (indicator 9.1.1)&lt;/a&gt;. Our project’s methodology can produce figures for every country in the world and was presented at the UN World Data Forum in Dubai. The project won the inaugural Government Science and Engineering Geography in Government Award. This work led to the World Bank reclassifying the indicator from Tier 3 to Tier 2. Tier 2 indicators have internationally established methodologies and standards available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also sourcing data and analysing geographic data to tackle Goal 15 (indicators 15.1.1, 15.1.2 and 15.4.1.) Spatial disaggregation of forest area as a percentage of total land area (indicator 15.1.1) for the whole of UK is now available. This data is available at country and local authority level. It is available for years 2015 to 2017 for Great Britain and 2018 for Northern Ireland. Data showing the proportion of important sites for terrestrial and freshwater biodiversity that are covered by protected areas (indicator 15.1.2) should follow shortly. We are also working on coverage by protected areas of important sites for biodiversity (indicator 15.4.1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried out exploratory work on marine protected areas for SDG target 14.5 (indicator 14.5.1). We have also worked on national exclusive economic zones managed using ecosystem-based approaches for SDG target 14.2 (indicator 14.2.1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the work we are doing with other departments, please &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-envelope&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&quot;&gt;email us at SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/funded-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/funded-work.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Data partners</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital Accessibility Testing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The commitment to “leave no one behind” is central to the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). It extends to making our digital content accessible and functional for all users regardless of any disability or physical impairment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment-uk.github.io/public/blog/accessible-definition.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image showing the dictionary definitions of the word accessible.&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our SDG data site is still in a testing phase, so we are using the ‘alpha’ label. We want to move the site to the next phase known as ‘beta’. Before we can label the site as beta it has to reach the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) ‘AA’ standard, as well as other Government Digital Service criteria. This is a universally-recognised standard, designed to guarantee that assessed websites reach the predetermined accessibility criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We updated some of the site’s features before it was tested, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;making data tables and menus keyboard compatible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improving the high-contrast feature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;adding descriptive labels and alternative text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tested the improvements on a range of desktop and mobile devices using a variety of browsers and screen-readers.
The Digital Accessibility Centre tested the data site against the WCAG ‘AA’ standard in July 2019. The newly-accessible site was re-tested in July 2019 and passed, &lt;a href=&quot;http://digitalaccessibilitycentre.org/index.php/office-for-national-statistics-sdg&quot;&gt;receiving ‘AA’ certification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With ‘AA’ standard achieved, the UK SDG data site is now considered accessible to all users. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-sdg/open-sdg/releases/tag/0.8.0&quot;&gt;new code release&lt;/a&gt; (0.8.0) included these accessibility updates on the shared code repository &lt;a href=&quot;https://open-sdg.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;‘Open SDG’&lt;/a&gt;. This means that any country is able to use these updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about what tools the site is compatible with and any know issues, see our &lt;a href=&quot;/sdg-indicators/accessibility-statement/&quot;&gt;accessibility statement&lt;/a&gt;, or please &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-envelope&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&quot;&gt;email us at SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/accessibility.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/accessibility.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Accessibility</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using APIs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently, our UK SDG data site requires data files to be in a specific format. This means that we have to reformat data that is in a different format in order to make it usable on the site . We are looking to automate the process of updating the data we report. To do this we are working with Application Programming Interfaces (APIs), which allows two software applications to communicate. APIs are commonly used by websites across the internet to automate updates and changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to use APIs that will work with data published online on a different website. For example, the ONS Gross Domestic Product (GDP) per head time series has a supporting API which makes the data available in a format we can use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have written software program code to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enable our data site to link with APIs used by other websites reporting data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the relevant new figures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Format the results so they are usable on our site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Print our indicator files ready to go on our site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently using APIs to update 15 different indicators. By automating these updates, we are able to report the latest data faster. To date we have concentrated on developing API communication with ONS websites. We are investigating which other websites we can connect to using APIs in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the work we are doing with APIs, please &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-envelope&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&quot;&gt;email us at SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/APIs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/updates/2019/11/04/APIs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Automation</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
