<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>U.K. Indicators For The Sustainable Development Goals</title>
    <description>Data Platform Prototype</description>
    <link>/sdg-indicators/</link>
    <atom:link href="/sdg-indicators/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 21:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 21:43:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What we do</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-what-are-the-sustainable-development-goals-sdgs&quot;&gt;1. What are the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs)?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, all member states of the United Nations signed up to the 17 Sustainable Development Goals. They set measurable aims for improving our world. Each goal covers a different aspect of life: poverty, hunger, education, equality, the environment, justice, economy and so on. They all have targets and indicators we aim to achieve by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United Nations will collect and catalogue data from each country to monitor progress towards achieving the goals. A central principle of the goals is to make sure we “Leave No-one Behind”. With that in mind, all the reported data must be disaggregated by sex, age, geography, race, ethnicity, disability, migratory status and income, where applicable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the UK, Office for National Statistics (ONS) is responsible for reporting the country’s data to the United Nations. We will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;source the appropriate UK data for the global indicators&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;provide data to the international organisations responsible for each indicator, known as Custodian Agencies, who will report them to the United Nations&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;analyse the data so that we can put it into context&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;make the data available to everybody using an online tool and supporting reports&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://onsdigital.github.io/sdg-indicators/public/sdgs.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of sustainable development goals logos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-latest-news&quot;&gt;2. Latest news&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;november-2017&quot;&gt;November 2017&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;sdgs-reporting-platform&quot;&gt;SDGs reporting platform&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “alpha” version of our SDGs reporting platform was launched. The site is based on an open source version developed by the United States government. We continue to work with the US and CODE on developments and would appreciate your feedback – please send your comments to sustainabledevelopment@ons.gov.uk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first progress report, “Sustainable Development Goals: progress and possibilities”, is published. It is on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/articles/sustainabledevelopmentgoalstakingstockprogressandpossibilities/november2017&quot;&gt;ONS website&lt;/a&gt; and on the publications page of this reporting platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sdgs-consultation&quot;&gt;SDGs consultation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our consultation on SDGs has closed. The purpose of the consultation was to seek views on our approach to measuring and reporting UK progress against the global SDGs indicators. The link to the report is below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-publications&quot;&gt;3. Publications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;february-2019---what-is-the-difference-between-sex-and-gender&quot;&gt;February 2019 - What is the difference between sex and gender?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are exploring concepts that are important to the Sustainable Development Goals. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/articles/whatisthedifferencebetweensexandgender/2019-02-21&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; explains the differences between sex and gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;november-2018---sustainable-development-goals-in-the-uk-an-update-on-progress&quot;&gt;November 2018 - Sustainable Development Goals in the UK: An update on progress&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/articles/sustainabledevelopmentgoalstakingstockprogressandpossibilities/november2018&quot;&gt;second report summarising the progress made&lt;/a&gt; towards measuring the global Sustainable Development Goals over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;october-2018---using-innovative-methods-to-report-against-the-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;October 2018 - Using innovative methods to report against the Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/articles/usinginnovativemethodstoreportagainstthesustainabledevelopmentgoals/2018-10-22&quot;&gt;outcome of a project aimed at exploring new ways of producing and communicating geographical data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;july-2018---inclusive-data-charter-action-plan-for-the-global-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;July 2018 - Inclusive data charter action plan for the global Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Office for National Statistics has partnered with the Global Partnership for Sustainable Development Data to improve the quality, quantity and availability of inclusive data. The report can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/methodologies/inclusivedatacharteractionplanfortheglobalsustainabledevelopmentgoals&quot;&gt;ONS website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;19-march-2018---uk-data-gaps&quot;&gt;19 March 2018 - UK data gaps&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/articles/ukdatagapsinclusivedataactionplantowardstheglobalsustainabledevelopmentgoalindicators/2018-03-19&quot;&gt;first report on UK data gaps&lt;/a&gt; for reporting progress towards the global Sustainable Development Goal indicators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;11-december-2017---consulation-findings&quot;&gt;11 December 2017 - Consulation findings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have analysed the feedback and it is published on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://consultations.ons.gov.uk/sustainable-development-goals/ons-approach-to-measuring-reporting-sdgs-in-the-uk/&quot;&gt;ONS website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;9-november-2017--sustainable-development-goals-progress-and-possibilities&quot;&gt;9 November 2017 – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/articles/sustainabledevelopmentgoalstakingstockprogressandpossibilities/november2017&quot;&gt;Sustainable Development Goals: progress and possibilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks at how much data have been collected for the global SDGs indicators by ONS for the UK. It also explains what work we are doing to measure progress towards the SDGs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Narrative reports will be listed by goal on the publications page of our SDG website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-august-2016--how-should-the-uk-report-progress-towards-the-sustainable-development-goals-a-summary-of-responses-from-non-governmental-organisations-pdf-711kb&quot;&gt;5 August 2016 – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/file?uri=/aboutus/whatwedo/programmesandprojects/sustainabledevelopmentgoals/howshouldtheukreportprogresstowardsthesustainabledevelopmentgoals.pdf&quot;&gt;How should the UK report progress towards the Sustainable Development Goals? A summary of responses from non-governmental organisations. (PDF, 711KB)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-want-to-know-more&quot;&gt;4. Want to know more?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UK data for the SDGs indicators can be found on this reporting platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information about Sustainable Development Goals can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.un.org/sustainabledevelopment/sustainable-development-goals/&quot;&gt;United Nations website&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globalgoals.org/&quot;&gt;Global Goals website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information about the technical process of developing the indicator framework can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/iaeg-sdgs/&quot;&gt;United Nations Inter-Agency and Expert Group on Sustainable Development Goal Indicators (IAEG-SDGs) webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-contact-us&quot;&gt;5. Contact us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow us on Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/StatSteel&quot;&gt;@StatSteel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ONS recognises the importance of working with all stakeholders, within and outside government. We are keen to hear your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To contact the ONS Sustainable Development Goals team please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&quot;&gt;SustainableDevelopment@ons.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sdg-indicators/news/2019/07/05/what-we-do.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sdg-indicators/news/2019/07/05/what-we-do.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
